<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
		<name>Armor</name>
		<update version="0.2.0">
			<file name="items-wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AstroSnout/aurora-wedrin/master/setting-specific-wedrin/items-wondrous.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Hat of Protection" type="Magic Item" source="Setting Specific (Wedrin)" id="ID_SSW_MAGIC_ITEM_HAT_OF_PROTECTION">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to AC and saving throws while you wear this hat.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">hat, armor, saving throw</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1" />		
			<stat name="strength:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="dexterity:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="wisdom:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="charisma:save:misc" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
    <element name="Diplomatic Gloves" type="Magic Item" source="Setting Specific (Wedrin)" id="ID_SSW_MAGIC_ITEM_DIPLOMATIC_GLOVES">
		<description>
			<p>These gloves have 3 charges. While wearing them you can expend a number of charges to cast one of the following spells with a range of touch:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Charm Person (expends 1 charge)</li>
				<li>Fast Friends (expends 2 charges)</li>
				<li>Modify Memory (expends 3 charges)</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">The gloves have a 50% chance to regain an expended charge daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">hands, gloves, armor, modify memory, fast friends, charm person</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Shard of Broken Identities" type="Magic Item" source="Setting Specific (Wedrin)" id="ID_SSW_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARD_OF_BROKEN_IDENTITIES">
		<description>
			<p>This small, crystalline ruby shard pulses with a dim, ever-changing light. It is believed to be a counduit between alternate realities, allowing the user to assume an identity from a different alternate timeline.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Assume Identity.</b></i> The attuned user can focus on the crystal for 1 minute to transfrom into a single identity stored within the crystal. You can do this action once per long rest, without any downsides. On every subsequent use during the same day, the user must make an increasingly difficult Wisdom saving throw. The DC of this effect starts at 5, doubling after every use. The DC resets to its original value after a long rest. On a fail, the user succumbs to the effects of a <i>Feeblemind</i> spell until they finish a long rest, or the effect is ended by greater restoration, heal or wish spell. The item is considered "used" on a fail as well, increasing the DC for subsequent use accordingly for the rest of the day.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Find Alternate Paths.</b></i> The attuned user can spend 1 hour to look through the crystal, discovering a new possible path towards an identity. Once a connection is found, the new identity is memorized within the crystal. This process takes an additional hour for each identity stored within the shard.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Remove Alternate Path. </b></i> The attuned user can spend 1 hour to look through the crystal, wiping an existing path from the shard's memory. Once the process is finished, an identity is forgotten from the shard. This process takes an additional hour for each identity stored within the shard.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shard, gem</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a fey creature">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Cloak of Ever-Changing Fashion" type="Magic Item" source="Setting Specific (Wedrin)" id="ID_SSW_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOAK_OF_EVERCHANGING_FASHION">
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this cloak, you can use a bonus action to change the style, color, and apparent quality of the garment. The cloak's weight doesn't change. Regardless of its appearance, the cloak can't be anything but a cloak. Although it can duplicate the appearance of other magic cloaks, it doesn't gain their magical properties.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can also use a bonus action to speak the cloaks command word and cause your outfit to assume the appearance of a normal set of clothing or some other kind of outfit. You decide what it looks like, including color, style, and accessories, but the outfit retains its normal bulk and weight. The illusory appearance lasts until you use this property again or remove the cloak.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fashion, shift, change</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulder</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Whistle of Telepathy" type="Magic Item" source="Setting Specific (Wedrin)" id="ID_SSW_MAGIC_ITEM_WHISTLE_OF_TELEPATHY">
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can blow the whistle to possibly establish a telepathic connection with a specific creature for 1 minute. The specific creature with whom you're establishing this connection is determined at the time the item is created. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">whistle, telepathy</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Djinni Shell" type="Magic Item" source="Setting Specific (Wedrin)" id="ID_SSW_MAGIC_ITEM_DJINNI_SHELL">
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can whisper into the shell to summon the Djinni that originally gave this item away. The Djinni appears on the closest surface of open sea water, ready to aid the whistler and his companions.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shell, djinni</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>